Guide to the Gertrud Lackschewitz Papers 1839-2008 (bulk 1890-1984)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
- German Immigrants in the United States Research Files, 1839-1984; Series VI; 1.0 linear foot
  - The Coming of the Russian Mennonites: An Episode in the Settling of the Last Frontier, 1874-1884, 1927 (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Russian-Germans, 1927-1976 and undated (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Letters Written in German from Russia, 1932 (Box-folder 6/5)
  - German Language Instructional Material, 1945 and undated (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Religion and Ethnicity, 1953-1985 and undated (Box-folder 6/7)
  - "An Inquiry into the Hutterian German Dialect", 1960 (Box-folder 6/8)
  - "German Americans and Neutrality in the 1916 Elections", 1961 (Box-folder 6/9)
  - German Language Newspapers, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Society for German-American Studies, 1979-1985 and undated (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Immigration History Newsletter, November 1980 (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Natural History-Article on Hutterite Children, February 1981 (Box-folder 6/13)
  - "Ethnic Leaderships Among German-Americans", September 8, 1981 (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Deutsche Einwanderung in die USA, German Immigration to the United States, Prints, 1683-1983, 1982 (Folder OS 16)
  - World War I, 1980-1981 and undated (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Articles and Papers, 1980-1982 and undated (Box-folder 6/16)
  - German Congregations, 1983 and undated (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Organizations and Historical Societies, 1984 and undated (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Pacific Northwest Council for Languages Conference, May 1984 and undated (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Bibliographies, undated (Box-folder 7/4)
  - Experiences from my Missionary Life in the Dakotas, undated (Box-folder 7/5)
  - Hutterite Religion, undated (Box-folder 7/6)
  - Immigration Maps, undated (Box-folder 7/7)
  - The Lutheran Guard, undated (Box-folder 7/8)
- Germans in Europe, 1864-1983; Series VII; 0.3 linear feet
  - Russian-Germans in Europe - Articles, Memoirs, Maps, 1864-1982 and undated (Box-folder 7/9)
  - German Documents, 1880-1907 (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Hostetter's Kalendar, 1890 (Box-folder 7/11)
  - "Die Logenbrueder Oelgemaelde," Print, 1899 (original) (Box-folder 7/12)
  - "Toward an Understanding of the Russia Germans", 1939 (Box-folder 7/13)
  - German Magazines, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 7/14)
  - Andenken-Bilder, Souvenir Picture from Neuruppin, Germany, undated (Folder OS 16)
- Photographs, 1896-1936; Series VIII; 1.0 linear foot
  - Marriage Certificate, April 14, 1898 (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Sylphonia Damen Gesang Verein, "Sylphonia Ladies Singing Club," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Prasidenten der auswartiegen Vereine, "Presidents of Foreign Club," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Missoula Maenner Chorus, "Missoula Men's Chorus," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Carl A. Weiss, Bundes-Präsident Helena, "President," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Arthur Seiler, Bundes-Dirigent, Helena, "Federal Conductor," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Hermann and Margareta Mayer Wedding Picture, 1898 (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Gallatin Maenner Chor - Bozeman, "Gallatin Men's Choir," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Damen Section Des Vereins "Germania" - Helena, "German Ladies' Society," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Gemischter Chor Des Vereins "Germania" - Helena, "German Mens' and Womens' Choral Society," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Bundes-Beamte, "Federal Officials," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Dirigenten der auswartigen Vereine, "Conductors of Foreign Clubs," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Beamten des Gesangvereins Germania, Helena, "Officials of the German Choral Society," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Unlabeled, Group of German Men in Uniforms, Arthur Seiler Director, With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Gesang Verein "Germania" - Helena, "German Choral Society," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Repraesentanten Der Gründung der Großloge des Ordens der Hermanns-Söhne in Helena, Montana, am 8. Juli, 1896, "Representatives of the founding of the Grand Lodge of the Order of the Sons of Hermann in Helena, Montana, on 8th July, 1896," With Negative (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Haupt Fest-Comite Des Zweiten Montana Saenger-Festes, " Main Committee for the Second Montana Singer Festival," With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Unlabeled Photographs, Interviewees of German Descent in Eastern Montana, undated (Box-folder 8/3)
  - Power, Church Repairs, Men Working, undated (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Power, Church Repairs, Women Watching, undated (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Fallon, Friedens Church, 1942 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - German Conference, Sidney, April 1946 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Worden, Bethlehem Congregational Church, undated (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Missoula, Emmanuel German Church (Congregational), undated (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Plevna, German Church, May 21, 1944 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Fallon, Wiltenberg Church, 1942 (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Bitterroot German Church, undated (Box-folder 8/4)
  - National Soldiers Home, Sawtelle, California, August 13, 1907 (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Germany, 1936 (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Butte Liederkranz, With Negative, May 1, 1910 (Box-folder 8/7)
  - German Picnic, Butte, Montana, With Negative, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Unlabeled Photograph, German Lutheran Church, Large Group of Children with Sunday School Teacher?, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Unlabeled Photograph, Group in front of Church, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Unlabeled Photograph, Group in front of Church, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Unlabeled Photograph, Large Group of Children, Confirmation?, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Father Hermann E. Mayer, Wife Margareta Vette Mayer, Children Hermann F. Mayer, Estella Mayer Wuhas, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Negative, Large Group, Butte, Montana, undated (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Unlabeled Photograph, Seven Individuals, With Negative, undated (Folder OS 17)
  - Pastor Hudtloff, Esther, Mike Busch, Flo, Bill Haller, Lena Urnhang, Hermie Urnhang (Mrs. J. Victor Wertling), With Negative, 1913 (Folder OS 17)
  - Walther League Convention, August 12, 1923 (Box 15)